Love who you want. It's good foreign policy.
Red, White & Royal Blue is a comedy, romance film directed by Matthew López.
After an altercation between Alex, the president's son, and Britain's Prince Henry at a royal event becomes
tabloid fodder, their long-running feud now threatens to drive a wedge in U.S./British relations.
When the rivals are forced into a staged truce, their icy relationship begins to thaw and
the friction between them sparks something deeper than they ever expected.
Alex Claremont-Diaz, played by Taylor Zakhar Perez.
Henry Hanover-Stuart Fox, played by Nicholas Galitzine.
Ellen Claremont, played by Uma Thurman.
Oscar Diaz, played by Clifton Collins Jr..
Nora Holleran, played by Rachel Hilson.
Zahra Bankston, played by Sarah Shahi.
Red, White & Royal Blue is a 2023 American romantic comedy film directed by Matthew López in his
feature film directorial debut, from a screenplay that he co-wrote with Ted Malawer.
The script is based on the 2019 novel by Casey McQuiston; it depicts a developing love affair between the son of
the president of the United States (Taylor Zakhar Perez) and a British prince (Nicholas Galitzine).
Clifton Collins Jr., Sarah Shahi, Rachel Hilson, Stephen Fry,
and Uma Thurman appear in supporting roles.
In 2019, Amazon Studios announced the film's
development with Greg Berlanti as a producer.
López was announced as director and co-writer with Malawer in 2021.
Casting announcements began in June 2022 with Zakhar Perez, Galitzine
and Thurman announced to play their respective roles.
The majority of the remaining cast was announced the following month.
Filming took place in England between June and August 2022.
Red, White & Royal Blue premiered at the BFI IMAX in London on July 22,
2023, and was released on Amazon Prime Video on August 11.
It received positive reviews from critics, and was nominated for
Outstanding Television Movie at the 76th Primetime Emmy Awards.
It is the last film released under the Amazon Studios name before the
studio was rebranded as Amazon MGM Studios a month later.
A sequel, Red, White & Royal Wedding, is in development with
Zakhar Perez and Galitzine set to return.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
politics, prince, royal family, royalty.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.